Register of the John H. Bunzel papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John H. Bunzel papers
1949-2004
87001
Bunzel, John H., 1924-
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
47 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 1 oversize box (21.7 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, correspondence, minutes, grant proposals, memoranda, reports, studies, hearing transcripts, printed matter, and photographs related to political science, administration of San Jose State University, student radicalism at San Francisco State University, activities of the Institute for Educational Affairs in funding academic research projects, and activities of the Civil Rights Commission in monitoring the status of civil rights in the United States, such as investigating allegations of race or sex discrimination in voting, employment, or housing and considering affirmative action and comparable worth concepts.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1987 with an increment in 2005.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
James Babb papers, Hoover Institution Archives
San Jose State Office of the Presidents, John Bunzel records, San Jose State University
Biographical Note
1924 Born, New York City, New York
1937-1942 Attended Kent School, Kent, Connecticut
1943-1946 Served in the United States Army
1948 AB in political science from Princeton University
1949 MA in sociology from Columbia University
1953-1956 Taught at San Francisco State College
1954 PhD in political science from the University of California at Berkeley
1956-1957 Taught at Michigan State University
1957-1963 Taught at Stanford University
1959-1961 Director, Northern California Citizenship Clearing House
1962 Author, The American Small Businessman
1962-1963 President, Northern California Political Science Association
1963-1970 Taught at San Francisco State College
1964 Author, Issues of American Public Policy
1967 Author, Anti-Politics in America
1968 California delegate, Democratic National Convention
1969 Awarded Presidential Award from the Northern California Political Science Association
1970-1978 President, San Jose State University
1974 Awarded Certificate of Honor from the San Francisco Board of Supervisors
1976 Honorary doctor of laws, University of Santa Clara
1978- Fellow, Hoover Institution
1983 Author, New Force on the Left: Tom Hayden and the Campaign Against Corporate America
1983-1986 Commissioner, United States Commission on Civil Rights
1985 Editor, Challenge to American Schools: The Case for Standards and Values
1988 Editor, Political Passages: Journeys of Change through Two Decades, 1968-1988 Became a political commentator on a KCBS radio news program
1990 Received the Hubert Humphrey Award from the American Political Science Association
1992 Author, Race Relations on Campus: Stanford Students Speak
1998 Author, Affirmative Action in Higher Education: A Dilemma of Conflicting Principles
Scope and Content of Collection
The John H. Bunzel papers consist of speeches and writings, correspondence, minutes, grant proposals, memoranda, reports, studies, hearing transcripts, printed matter, and photographs related to political science, administration of San Jose State University, student radicalism at San Francisco State University, activities of the Institute for Educational Affairs in funding academic research projects, and activities of the Civil Rights Commission in monitoring the status of civil rights in the United States, such as investigating allegations of race or sex discrimination in voting, employment, or housing and considering affirmative action and comparable worth concepts.
Over his career, Bunzel served as a professor of political science, academic president, and Hoover Institution fellow. The Biographical file contains a curriculum vitae detailing Bunzel's career, as well as report cards and photographs. For articles about Bunzel, see the clippings in the speeches and writings series, as well as the San Jose State University file.
The collection contains Correspondence, mainly dating from the 1990s, which includes letters to or from Morris B. Abram, John Kerry, Edward Laurie, Stanley Mosk, Daniel Moynihan, Condoleezza Rice, and David Riesman. Several letters contain discussions of affirmative action issues.
Many of Bunzel's Speeches and writings also comment on affirmative action policies and civil rights issues. This file includes speeches, books, articles by Bunzel and about him, radio commentary, interviews, and chapter drafts for Race Relations on Campus, a book published in 1992 that examines issues of race at Stanford University.
The Professional activities file contains materials related to Bunzel's teaching career, as well as his role as the California delegate to the Democratic National Convention of 1968 and a Hoover Institution fellow. Bunzel was a professor at San Francisco State University from 1953 to 1956 and from 1963 to 1970, an era that saw student unrest and protests. During a lengthy strike in the 1960s, Bunzel was a target of student protesters, suffering disruptions while teaching and threats. This period of student radicalism at San Francisco State University is documented in this file.
Bunzel served as president of San Jose State University from 1970 to 1978. Under his leadership, the university established programs in religious studies, Jewish studies, and women's studies; changed its name from San Jose State College to San Jose State University; and hired more women into high-level administrative positions than any other California State University at that time. The San Jose State University file contains speeches, clippings, and letters documenting Bunzel's activities as president.
Bunzel served on the board of directors for the Institute for Educational Affairs (IEA), which later merged with the Madison Center to become the Madison Center for Educational Affairs. The IEA was an educational foundation established in 1978 with the goal of supporting democratic capitalism. The collection includes materials from board meetings of the IEA, such as agendas, minutes, grant proposals, and reports.
In 1983, President Reagan appointed Bunzel to the United States Commission on Civil Rights, a federal agency established in 1957 to investigate civil rights issues. In 1986, Bunzel called for the resignation of Chairman Clarence Pendleton and did not seek reappointment after the expiration of his term of service. The United States Commission on Civil Rights file includes meeting materials, memoranda, and consultation/hearing binders related to issues of comparable worth, affirmative action, and fair housing. Memoranda often summarize court cases and have attached reports.
The Audiovisual material includes sound recordings of Bunzel's speeches, as well as recordings of events at San Jose State University, such as Bunzel's inauguration as president and his "farewell roast" upon leaving that position. This file contains a videotape of Bunzel being interviewed at Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory, which includes his comments on Edward Teller. The Oversize material and ephemera contain clippings and a coffee mug imprinted with an article about Bunzel.
Source: San Jose State University. SJSU Presidents. http://www.sjsu.edu/about_sjsu/history/presidents/
Institute for Educational Affairs (New York, N.Y.); San Jose State University.; United States Commission on Civil Rights.; Affirmative action programs--United States.; Civil rights--United States.; Education--United States.; Equal pay for equal work--United States.; Learning and scholarship--United States.; Political science.; Radicalism--United States.; Research--United States.; Student movements--United States.; United States--Race relations.; Women--United States.
- Biographical file, 1942-2004
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes curriculum vitae, clippings, photographs, and report cards.
  - General, 1942-1969 (Folder 1: 1)
    Includes report cards and photographs
  - Biographical information, undated (Folder 1: 2)
  - Clippings, 1990, 2004 (Folder 1: 3)
    General note
    See also clippings in Speeches and writings
  - Curriculum vitae, undated (Folder 1: 4)
- Correspondence, 1970-2004
  Includes letters to and from various correspondents, including Morris B. Abram, John Kerry, Edward Laurie, Stanley Mosk, Daniel Moynihan, Condoleezza Rice, and David Riesman. Some letters contain discussions of affirmative action issues.
  - 1970 (Folder 1: 5)
    Contains a letter to Alex Sherriffs
  - 1981 (Folder 1: 6)
    Contains a letter from William E. Simon
  - 1988-1992 (Folder 1: 7)
    Contains letters from David Riesman
  - 1990 (Folder 1: 8-9)
    Includes letters to or from Morris B. Abram, David Armor, David Bernstein, Bernard Davis, George Deukmejian, Murray Friedman, Edward Laurie, Leslie Lenkowsky, Bill Leonard, John McCarthy, Stanley Mosk, James F. Murphy, Harvey Schechter, Scott Shuger, Julian C. Stanley, and Mark Weideman
  - 1991 (Folder 1: 10-11)
    Includes letters to or from Morris B. Abram, Randy Hamilton, Fred Hargadon, Edward Laurie, Philip Lyons, and Stanley Mosk
  - 1992 (Folder 1: 12-14)
    Includes letters to or from William Allen, Milton Friedman, John Kerry, George R. LaNoue, Glenn Loury, Daniel Moynihan, David Riesman, and Helene Whitson
  - 1993 (Folder 1: 15-16)
    Includes letters to or from Robert Hess, George R. LaNoue, Sue Linnig, Edward Laurie, and Sheldon Meyer
  - 1994 (Folder 2: 1)
    Includes letters to or from Martha Bayles, David J. Fischer, George Hume, Stanley Mosk, John Raisian, and David S. Saurman
  - 1995 (Folder 2: 2)
    Includes letters to or from William German, Linda Gottfredson, Michael Heise, Edward J. Laurie, Julian Lesser, Stanley Mosk, Sandra Powell, John Raisian, Condoleezza Rice, Harvey Schechter, Jeffrey D. Wallin, and Rita Zurcher
  - 1996 (Folder 2: 3)
    Includes letters to or from Chandler Davidson, Douglas Foster, Bernard Johnston, Edward Laurie, Tom Metzger, Roger Pilon, Austin Ranney, David Riesman, Peter Rose, Jerry Shroder, and Abigail Wolf
  - 1997 (Folder 2: 4)
    Includes letters to or from George P. Carter, William Clinton, Susan Golding, Thomas Henriksen, Kay Seymour House, Tamar Jacoby, Edward Laurie, Ted Lucas, John Raisian, and Jeffrey Wallin
  - 1998 (Folder 2: 5)
    Includes letters to or from Camila Alire, Johnathan Bean, Pat Baker, Tamar Jacoby, Tom Metzger, Stanley Mosk, Jack Scott, and Tomas Sowell
  - 1999 (Folder 2: 6)
    Includes letters to or from Richard M. Kaplan, Stanley Mosk, Judith Shoolery, James P. Walsh, and Helene Whitson
  - 2000 (Folder 2: 7)
    Includes letters to or from Gloria Hom, George Moore, Daniel J. Socolow, and Curry Stypula
  - 2003 (Folder 2: 8)
    Contains a letter from Alice Lynn
  - 2004 (Folder 2: 9)
    Contains a letter from Randy H. Hamilton
- Speeches and writings, 1949-2004
  Includes clippings, typescripts, and monographs related to civil rights issues and education.
  - Untitled draft, undated (Folder 2: 10)
  - Affirmative action articles, undated (Folder 2: 11)
  - "Affirmative Action in Higher Education", undated (Folder 2: 12-13)
  - "The Anatomy of Affirmative Action", undated (Folder 3: 1)
  - "Bakke v. the University of California: Preferential Admissions and the Shadow of Race", undated (Folder 3: 2)
  - "Beyond the Rhetoric of President Bush on Civil Rights", undated (Folder 3: 3)
  - "The Civil Rights Commission: Sense and Nonsense", undated (Folder 3: 4)
  - Clippings, undated (Folder 3: 5)
  - "A Court Decision on Affirmative Action: A CSUC Case Study", undated (Folder 3: 6)
  - "The Democrats Take Stock - And Cash Too," "Public Opinion and Affirmative Action," and "Public Opinion and Public Policy", undated (Folder 3: 7)
  - Edison Project letter to Cynthia Patrick, undated (Folder 3: 8)
  - "Edward Teller: A Personal Remembrance ", undated (Folder 3: 9)
  - "Group Representation in Undergraduate Admissions: The Affirmative Action Dimension at UC Berkeley", undated (Folder 3: 10)
  - "Introduction to Affirmative Action," speech note cards, undated (Folder 3: 11)
  - "Labor in San Francisco - A Political Profile", undated (Folder 3: 12)
  - Leadership speech, undated (Folder 3: 13)
  - "Maledictions and Moral Issues in Academe: An Ex-Administrator's Partisan Review", undated (Folder 3: 14)
  - "Minority Faculty Hiring", undated (Folder 3: 15)
  - "Minority 'Set Asides'", undated (Folder 3: 16)
  - "The New Equality Principle: To Each According to Her Worth", undated (Folder 3: 17)
  - "Preferences in College Admissions: Time for Full Disclosure", undated (Folder 3: 18)
  - "Race at the Harvard Law School, undated (Folder 3: 19)
  - "The 'Reagan Revolution' and Civil Rights", undated (Folder 3: 20)
  - "Rescuing Equality", undated (Folder 3: 21)
  - Speech note cards, undated (Folder 3: 22-23)
  - Speech on college problems, undated (Folder 3: 24)
  - Speech on drugs, undated (Folder 3: 25)
  - "The Supreme Court's Decisions on Civil Rights: The Challenge to Congress", undated (Folder 4: 1)
  - "The Thorny Issue of Gay Marriage", undated (Folder 4: 2)
  - "When Does Affirmative Action Turn Negative?", undated (Folder 4: 3)
  - "A Year in the Life of a Liberal in the Middle", undated (Folder 4: 4)
    Describes Bunzel's experience during the 1969 protests at San Francisco State College (now San Francisco State University)
  - "Some Socialist Stocktaking of England's Nationalization Program," master's thesis, typescript and notes, 1949 (Folder 4: 5)
  - The American Small Business Man, 1962
    - Monograph, 1962 (Folder 4: 6)
    - Reviews, 1962-1963 (Folder 4: 7)
  - Issues in American Public Policy, 1964 (Folder 4: 8)
  - Anti-Politics in America, 1967
    - Alfred A. Knopf file, 1964-1967 (Folder 4: 9)
    - Monograph, 1967 (Folder 5: 1)
    - Reviews, 1967-1968 (Folder 5: 2)
  - "Black Studies at San Francisco State", 1968 (Folder 5: 3)
  - Speeches, 1968-1969 (Folder 5: 4-5)
  - Speech note cards, 1968-1969 (Folder 5: 6-7)
  - Clippings, 1969 (Folder 6: 1)
  - White House "Universities Dinner" correspondence, 1969 (Folder 6: 2)
  - "Some Reflections on Student Participation and Representation", 1970 (Folder 6: 3)
  - "Comments on Faculty Workload Standards", 1971 (Folder 6: 4)
  - "The Faculty Strike at San Francisco State College", 1971 (Folder 6: 5)
  - "Do Colleges Practice Reverse Bias?", 1972 (Folder 6: 6)
  - "The Politics of Quotas", 1972 (Folder 6: 7)
  - "New Threats to Academic Freedom", 1973-1974 (Folder 6: 8)
  - San Jose Mercury News columns, 1973-1980 (Folder 6: 9-10)
  - American College Public Relations Association meeting, speech, 1974 (Folder 6: 11)
  - "The Social Context of Inquiry: Problems of Forbidden and Discouraged Knowledge," 140th meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, speech, 1974 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Speeches, 1974-1979 (Folder 6: 13)
  - Clippings, 1975 (Folder 6: 14)
  - "Some Guiding Principles: A Statement of Values," speech, 1975 (Folder 6: 15)
  - "Some Tracks in the Ivory Tower", 1975, 1978 (Folder 6: 16)
  - United Way, speech, 1976 (Folder 6: 17)
  - Clippings, 1977 (Folder 6: 18)
  - Speeches, 1977-1978 (Folder 6: 19)
  - Clippings, 1978 (Folder 6: 20)
  - "Time to Clear the Air on Civil Rights Policy", 1978-1979 (Folder 6: 21)
  - "Affirmative Action, Negative Results", 1979 (Folder 7: 1)
  - Clippings, 1979 (Folder 7: 2)
  - "Politics and Pressure in Picking a College President" and "How Gov. Brown Put Pressure on Board of Trustees", 1979-1980 (Folder 7: 3-4)
  - Stanford Alumni Conference, speech, 1979 (Folder 7: 5)
  - Anti-Defamation League Workshop, speech, 1980 (Folder 7: 6)
  - "Bunzel: Doing What Most Dream About", 1980 (Folder 7: 7)
  - Clippings, 1980 (Folder 7: 8-9)
  - "For Freedom - Will We Pay the Price?" commencement address at DeAnza College, 1980 (Folder 7: 10)
  - Notes on article by Judy Miller, 1980 (Folder 7: 11)
  - ACLU articles, 1981 (Folder 7: 12)
  - "Affirmative Action," conference of Christians and Jews, San Jose, 1981 (Folder 7: 13)
  - [Anu?] Jewish Congress, 1981 (Folder 7: 14)
  - Clippings, 1981 (Folder 7: 15-16)
  - "A Critical Review of the Statement of Affirmative Action in the 1980s of the United States Commission on Civil Right", 1981 (Folder 7: 17)
  - "The Politics of Human Rights", 1981 (Folder 7: 18)
  - "Proposed Statement on Affirmative Action by the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights: A Critical Review, 1981 (Folder 7: 19)
  - "A Statement Prepared for the Senate Judiciary Subcommittee on the Constitution", 1981 (Folder 7: 20)
  - "A Statement Prepared for the Senate Labor Committee", 1981 (Folder 7: 21)
  - Typescripts, 1981 (Folder 7: 22)
    Includes "Today's ACLU Marches to Too Many Drummers," "Evolution Vs. Creationism," and "Anti-Abortionists See Only Good and Evil, Right and Wrong"
  - Clippings, 1982 (Folder 7: 23)
  - Clippings (Contd.), 1982 (Folder 8: 1)
  - "The Democrats and Class Conflict", 1982 (Folder 8: 2)
  - "Anti-Defamation League", 1983 (Folder 8: 3)
  - "Civil Rights Views and Activities", 1983 (Folder 8: 4)
  - Clippings, 1983 (Folder 8: 5-6)
  - College of Law, University of Wyoming, speech, 1983 (Folder 8: 7)
  - "Equality, Yes - But Can We Have Excellence Too?" University of Wyoming public address, 1983, undated (Folder 8: 8)
  - Executive Order 11246, circa 1983-1986 (Folder 8: 9)
  - Firing Line transcript, "Do Civil Rights Equal Affirmative Action?", 1983 (Folder 8: 10)
  - Hoover Institution Forum, speech note cards, 1983 (Folder 8: 11)
  - List of documents for computer account, 1983 (Folder 8: 12)
  - Merle Mooney memorial, 1983 (Folder 8: 13)
  - New Force on the Left
    - Monograph, 1983 (Folder 8: 14)
    - Reviews, 1983 (Folder 8: 15)
  - Stanford Medical Alumni Association, "Equality and Excellence: Can We Have Both?" speech, 1983 (Folder 8: 16)
  - University of Dallas commencement pamphlet, 1983 (Folder 8: 17)
  - AJC and Pacific Bell, speech, 1984 (Folder 8: 18)
  - Clippings, 1984 (Folder 8: 19-20)
  - "Ethnic Theme Houses at Stanford", 1984-1985
    See also Race Relations on Campus, 1992
    - Completed interviews, 1984-1985 (Folder 8: 21)
    - Completed interviews (Contd.), 1984-1985 (Folder 9: 1)
    - Stanford theme house survey, 1974-1985 (Folder 9: 2-3)
  - Hoover Institution panel, speech note cards, 1984 (Folder 9: 4)
  - "On the Debate Over Civil Rights", 1984 (Folder 9: 5)
    Includes correspondence
  - California students and merit article, 1985 (Folder 9: 6-7)
    Includes correspondence and research
  - Challenge to American Schools: The Case for Standards and Values, 1985
    - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Folder 10: 1)
    - Monograph, 1985 (Folder 10: 2)
  - Clippings, 1985 (Folder 10: 3-4)
  - Clippings, 1986 (Folder 10: 5-6)
  - Hoover Institution Board of Overseers Semi-Annual Meeting, speech, 1986 (Folder 10: 7)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1986 (Folder 10: 8-9)
  - Berkshire Learning Center 15th Annual Commencement, speech, 1987 (Folder 10: 10)
    See also University of Phoenix commencement
  - Clippings, 1987 (Folder 10: 11)
  - "Politics - Directions and Trends", circa 1987 (Folder 11: 1)
  - Clippings, 1988 (Folder 11: 2)
  - KCBS radio show, 1988 (Folder 11: 3)
  - National Association of Scholars, World Trade Center, speech, 1988 (Folder 11: 4)
  - Political Passages: Journeys of Change through Two Decades, 1968-1988
    - "Liberal in the Middle", 1988 (Folder 11: 5)
    - Monograph, 1988 (Folder 11: 6)
    - "Reflections on the 1960s-1970s", 1988 (Folder 11: 7)
    - Reviews, 1988 (Folder 11: 8)
  - "Politics 1988," San Jose Rotary, speech note cards (Folder 11: 9)
  - Presidential elections speech, 1988 (Folder 11: 10)
  - California Newspaper Publishers Association, speech note cards, 1989 (Folder 11: 11)
  - Clippings, 1989 (Folder 11: 12)
  - Speech notes, circa 1989 (Folder 12: 1)
  - Stanford Singles of Los Angeles, speech note cards, 1989 (Folder 12: 2)
  - "1990 Elections", circa 1990 (Folder 12: 3)
  - "The 1990 Mid-Term Elections," speech (Folder 12: 4)
  - "Affirmative Action and Diversity in Higher Education," Claremont McKenna College, speech, 1990 (Folder 12: 5)
  - "Between Power and Integration", circa 1990 (Folder 12: 6)
  - "Bunzel Says Colleges Use Affirmative Action to White Candidates From Faculty Hiring", 1990 (Folder 12: 7)
  - "Civil Rights, Yes - The Quota Mentality, No", circa 1990 (Folder 12: 8)
  - Clippings, 1990 (Folder 12: 9)
  - Humphrey Award speech, circa 1990 (Folder 12: 10)
  - Ohio State University, 1990 (Folder 12: 11)
  - San Jose Rotary 20th Anniversary, 1990 (Folder 12: 12)
  - "Testimony Submitted to the House Education and Labor Committee on H.R. 4000," with Abigail Thernstrom, 1990 (Folder 12: 13)
  - Clippings, 1991 (Folder 12: 14)
  - "Race, Racism and Equality", 1991, undated (Folder 12: 15)
  - Trustee retreat at Claremont Mckenna, 1991 (Folder 12: 16)
  - University of Phoenix commencement address, 1991 (Folder 12: 17)
    See also Berkshire Learning Center Commencement
  - "Bill Clinton and the Politics of Race and Equality", 1992 (Folder 12: 18)
  - Clippings, 1992 (Folder 12: 19)
  - Clippings, 1992-1994 (Folder 12: 20)
  - Hoover Institution Panel on Education Reform, speech note cards, 1992 (Folder 12: 21)
  - Hoover Institution Politics Panel, 1992-2000 (Folder 12: 22-23)
    Includes political preferences poll
  - Hoover Institution speech note cards, 1992-1994, undated (Folder 13: 1-2)
  - KCBS radio show, 1992 (Folder 13: 3)
  - Race Relations on Campus, 1992
    - Chapter drafts
      - "An Overview" and "Stanford and Its Students", 1991-1992 (Folder 13: 4)
      - "The Beethoven Incident", 1992 (Folder 13: 5)
      - "The Views and Experiences of Black and White Students", 1992 (Folder 13: 6)
      - "How Blacks and Whites Get Along", undated (Folder 13: 7)
      - "Three Student Profiles", undated (Folder 13: 8)
      - "Appendix: Ethnic Theme Houses", undated (Folder 13: 9)
    - Correspondence and reviews, 1991-1992 (Folder 14: 1)
    - Monograph, 1992 (Folder 14: 2)
  - "Sexual Harassment in Stanford's Medical School: Awaiting the Dean's Decision", circa 1992 (Folder 14: 3)
  - Clippings, 1993 (Folder 14: 4-5)
  - "Francis Villemain Memorial Lecture," San Jose State University, 1993 (Folder 14: 6)
  - "In Democracy's Shadow: A Defense of the University's Core Values", 1993, undated (Folder 14: 7)
  - Clippings, 1994 (Folder 14: 8)
  - National Association of Scholars Annual Meeting, 1993 (Folder 14: 9)
  - Community College League, Irvine, California, 1994 (Folder 14: 10)
  - "In Memory of Emerson 'Doc' Arends", 1994 (Folder 14: 11)
  - Stanford Men's Golf Club Annual Dinner, 1994 (Folder 14: 12)
  - "Why They Hate Clinton", 1994 (Folder 14: 13)
  - "Affirmative Action: Premises and Assumptions," speech, 1995 (Folder 14: 14)
  - Clippings, 1995 (Folder 14: 15)
  - Field Institute Annual Forum speech, 1995 (Folder 14: 16)
  - Golf Club Annual Dinner, Faculty Club, 1995 (Folder 14: 17)
  - 1996 election speeches (Folder 14: 18-19)
  - "Black Studies Revisited at San Francisco State," with Anita Grossman, 1996-1997 (Folder 14: 20)
  - Clippings, 1996 (Folder 14: 21)